<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-11-10T19:59:12-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Keiland W. Cooper</title><subtitle>The hub node of Keiland's online network</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Creating pretty figures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Figures/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating pretty figures" /><published>2022-09-12T14:11:27-07:00</published><updated>2022-09-12T14:11:27-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Figures</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Figures/">&lt;p&gt;For communicating science, a picture tells a thousand words. Indeed, almost everyone knows that one group that time after time comes out with stunning figures. Moreover, it’s hardly ever just for looks. Having high quality figures can help you tell your story, and more importantly, help the reader learn your science. Here are a few useful sites that have helped me improve my scientific illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;science-specific&quot;&gt;Science specific&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://smart.servier.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Smart Servier&lt;/a&gt; hosts a lot of well illustrated Medical images&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scidraw.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Scidraw&lt;/a&gt; also has a lot of great science vectors to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href=&quot;https://biorender.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Biorender&lt;/a&gt; is mostly a paid science illustration service and repository, it can be affordable to some labs and has a top notch and growing suite of illustrations and tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a similar business model to Bio-Render, &lt;a href=&quot;https://mindthegraph.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Mind the Graph&lt;/a&gt; also holds great scientific illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://phylopic.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Phylopic&lt;/a&gt; is an awesome repository of free silhouette images of animals, plants, and other life forms along the taxonomic tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CDC also has a repository! &lt;a href=&quot;https://phil.cdc.gov/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;phil.cdc.gov&lt;/a&gt; has science and health images with open licenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More general science images can also be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scienceimage.csiro.au/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;scienceimage.csiro.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also worth knowing about &lt;a href=&quot;https://scientificstock.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;scientificstock.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For neuroscience, some may be interested in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://scalablebrainatlas.incf.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;scalable brain atlas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;general-tools&quot;&gt;General tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenounproject.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Noun Project&lt;/a&gt; has icons for just about everything&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt; is a repository of pretty good stock photos and vectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As does &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freepik.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Freepik&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And stock vectors at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vecteezy.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vecteezy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikimedia&lt;/a&gt; also has open license photos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A really cool project is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dimensions.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dimensions&lt;/a&gt;, which is a database of dimensioned vectors documenting measurements of multiple objects&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;https://undraw.co/search&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Undraw&lt;/a&gt; has business-like clip-art you can change the color of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-tools&quot;&gt;Some tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An easy way to remove image backgrounds is &lt;a href=&quot;https://picwish.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;picwish&lt;/a&gt; (if you don’t want to fire up Photoshop)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it will pay well to learn Adobe Illustrator or Photoshop. Free open-source alternatives include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gimp.org/&quot;&gt;Gimp&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://inkscape.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Inkscape&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;services&quot;&gt;Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also paid services that will help design your figures for you. I’ve never used them, but they’re usually individual artists or agencies, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://catalyzingscience.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Catalyzing Science&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.somersault1824.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Somersault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-good-articles&quot;&gt;Some good articles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://crastina.se/guides/the-poster-design-hub/scientific-images/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; about science illustration services&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.addgene.org/early-career-researcher-toolbox-free-tools-for-making-scientific-graphics&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nice list&lt;/a&gt; of other science illustration tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a tip you think I should add? Please let me know &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwcooper.xyz/contact&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Keiland Cooper</name></author><summary type="html">For communicating science, a picture tells a thousand words. Indeed, almost everyone knows that one group that time after time comes out with stunning figures. Moreover, it’s hardly ever just for looks. Having high quality figures can help you tell your story, and more importantly, help the reader learn your science. Here are a few useful sites that have helped me improve my scientific illustrations.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/blog/blog-post-06.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/blog/blog-post-06.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Personal finance notes in academia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Finance-for-academics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Personal finance notes in academia" /><published>2022-08-12T14:11:27-07:00</published><updated>2022-08-12T14:11:27-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Finance-for-academics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Finance-for-academics/">&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, scientists wouldn’t have to worry about finances and could focus on their research. In reality, like every other sector, macro- and micro-economic trends guide the shape of science. This pinch of reality reveals the complex systems that pervade all levels of academia: funding agencies, state legislation, donors, graduate stipends, or undergraduate tuition. Similar to other academic topics, I found this complex area difficult to navigate as an early scientist. Particularly as a first generation student, who once didn’t know the difference between bursar and provost, despite its importance, it’s rarely explicitly taught. Since then, I’ve spent years in academia, learning about through osmosis, and even did an MBA to help wrap my head around it all. What follows is a collection of some of my notes on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finance-for-graduate-researchers&quot;&gt;Finance for graduate researchers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While finances may not dictate the type of research you dream of doing, it may help with your decision of where you will accomplish it. Finance in graduate school starts with thinking about your current financial situation and your goals. Later, as the offer letters come, sitting down, and factoring the details of them into your decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding metrics of comparison for your potential stipend can be tremendously useful towards better understanding your offer letter. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phdstipends.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;phdstipends.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has collected an open list of PhD stipends from around the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, comparing stipends between two universities depends on more than just the dollar amount. Each location’s cost of living varies, and thus should be taken into account. One method to do so is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://livingwage.mit.edu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;living wage calculator&lt;/a&gt;, that does many of the calculations for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For myself, it was important to set myself up psychologically for the extra task of managing finances as an early scientist. Articles like this one help with that mindset shift: “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/express/wp/2017/04/11/managing-finances-might-be-graduate-students-toughest-test/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Managing finances might be graduate students’ toughest test&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as blog articles that offer advice, such as “&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.r3ciprocity.com/how-to-survive-financially-as-a-graduate-or-doctoral-student/?nab=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Survive Financially as a Graduate or Doctoral Student&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or wonderful resources that offer an in-depth guide to navigating finances, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://pfforphds.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Personal Finance for PhD’s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common misconception is that graduate students in the US do not need to pay taxes on their graduate stipends or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/taxtopics/tc421&quot;&gt;fellowships&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, &lt;a href=&quot;https://grad.uci.edu/funding/tax-information/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this is not the case&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/p970.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;tax code&lt;/a&gt; does distinguish between the money paid by a graduate program for tuition and other education related expenses, which are often untaxed, and the stipend, money from the program for room, board, and other living expenses, which are often taxed. Same too for state taxes in many states. If money is not withdrawn automatically from your paycheck by your program, then you’ll likely need to make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/help/ita/am-i-required-to-make-estimated-tax-payments&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;quarterly estimated tax payments&lt;/a&gt;, four times per tax year to make up the difference. Rules will likely differ for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/p519.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;international students&lt;/a&gt; by specific circumstances. I really recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://pfforphds.com/taxes/&quot;&gt;this site&lt;/a&gt; to help you start navigating graduate school taxes. UCSD also has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://grad.ucsd.edu/_files/financial-support/taxes/CITGenTaxInfo.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;great guide&lt;/a&gt; for their students. As does the APA, though a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apa.org/gradpsych/features/2011/tax-tips&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bit old&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few other opportunities in your life where you can get a no-strings-attached sum of money as with scholarships and fellowships. Apply! There are lots of great intra and inter-university resources floating around. I wrote a bit about the large academic fellowships, such as the GRFP,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwcooper.xyz/GRFP-advice/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-brief-overview-of-personal-finance&quot;&gt;A brief overview of personal finance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll come out of the gate and qualify this by saying that there is not one strategy to build wealth. Rather, everyone’s own circumstances will alter what might work best, and the types of strategies that they’ll need to employ. From a bit of trial and error however, here’s one approach that has worked well for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to opt for a somewhat conservative saving approach, that attempts to meet goals that are staged one after the other. For me, the most important aspect to mitigate risk is to build towards a financial “safty net” of emergancy savings, and then building out from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First and foremost, pay off debts ASAP (Excluding mortgage)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Save at least 6 months of your current salary in cash accounts for emergencies&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your employer offers a 401k, max out yearly contributions&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open a Roth IRA, and max out yearly contributions&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Save at least 12 months current salary in cash accounts for emergencies&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Only then, if you have excess income:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Increase emergancy cash reserves&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start saving for bigger goals&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Investments outside of retirement (stocks, bonds, alternatives)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Increase donations&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Increase lifestyle costs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, getting there isn’t easy, but here’s what has worked for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Live below your means as much as possible
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t inflate your lifestyle costs at the same rate as your income increases&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open a savings account and work towards building your first $1,000 in emergency savings&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Start working on paying off your debts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once all debt is paid off, start growing emergency savings account to 3-6 months in savings&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start saving for retirement, start slow, but try to build up to 15-20% of your monthly salary
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Start with 401k if your employer has one&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Or / in addition to, open a Roth IRA&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then start targeting big financial goals: Save for your kids college, pay off a home, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reassess your goals at each step
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Change jobs? Add income source? Other investments?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Assess your risk levels&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Assess your economic environment&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never made a budget before, that’s always the first step to quantify your financial situation. At a high level, it all comes down to input vs output: how much are you earning vs how much are you spending? If the later exceeds the former, you either need to cut costs or find ways to increase your income. Otherwise, you can consider paying off debts or saving more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I like to think about the biggest expenditures the most. How much am I paying for rent? What are my largest bills? What expenditures surprise me the most? &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kwcooper/save-money-close-deals-clip-coupons-the-science-of-decision-making-1ba38181fb71&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Economic psychology teaches us&lt;/a&gt; that we’re likely to spend more time saving $1 on a cheeseburger, than on a car, despite the fact the amount is the same. Everyone harks on young folks for spending their money on “Avocados and Starbucks” but saving just $100 a month on rent or car payments can quickly absorb many of those types of discretionary costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/investing.png&quot; alt=&quot;XKCD-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-few-notes-on-investing&quot;&gt;A few notes on investing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself having saved enough money to pay off bills, create an emergency fund, and pay off debts, you might consider investing to increase your rate of return outside of bank cash accounts that provide minimal interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full treatment of investing is so far beyond the scope of these notes, but a few bits of info may be useful. For instance, the first lesson finance courses will teach is that of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/t/timevalueofmoney.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;time value of money&lt;/a&gt;. This core principle of finance states that a given sum of money is worth more now than the same amount will be at a future date. This is due to money’s earnings potential in the interim, primarily through investing. Thus, a delayed investment is a lost opportunity. Colloquially, this means that the best time to start investing was yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all investments, you must first and foremost consider the amount of risk you’re comfortable taking on. While they’re are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/041415/what-are-some-common-measures-risk-used-risk-management.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;multiple ways to quantify risk&lt;/a&gt;, generally, the higher an investments potential returns, the more risk you might take on. When thinking about risk, it is often worthwhile to consider your time horizon, that is, the amount of time until the money is needed. The greater the time horizon, the more risky an investment is allowed to be. It is far more ideal to take on more risk as a younger investor, with time to re-strategize, than an older one who may need that money soon to pay for retirement costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After considering your risk, there are four main types of investments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stocks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bonds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alternatives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re likely most familiar with cash investments, where your money goes into a bank. Interests rates, or the amount of money the bank pays you for the privilege of keeping your money, are small, often less than a percent, but these accounts have the least amount of risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second type are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/c/commonstock.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;stocks&lt;/a&gt;, which often means ownership in a publicly traded company. Say &lt;em&gt;Keiland’s Cupcakes&lt;/em&gt;, the number one cupcake company in the world, goes public. If you by 100 shares of the company at $10 one day, you will own a small percentage of &lt;em&gt;Keiland’s Cupcakes&lt;/em&gt;. Say in the future, the share price rises to $25 per share. If you sell your shares, then you’ll have $2500, a profit of $1500 (before taxes). However, stocks are risky, and there’s no guarantee the price will rise.  If &lt;em&gt;Keiland’s Cupcakes&lt;/em&gt; share price dips to $5, then you will have lost $500. Beyond the buy / sell price, you can also sometimes make money through dividends, or money paid regularly by a company to its shareholders from its profits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While stocks are ownership in a company, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/financial-edge/0312/the-basics-of-bonds.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;bonds&lt;/a&gt; are loans of the company’s debt. For instance, &lt;em&gt;Keiland’s Cupcakes&lt;/em&gt; also can raise money by issuing bonds and agreeing to pay you, the bond holder, interest payments on your loan to them. These payments will last until the bond reaches its maturity date, and the company repays you the price of the bond. While bonds typically are less risky than stocks, bonds can also change in value, based on market conditions. So if the price of the bond increases, you could also sell the bond to make a profit, or cut potential losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last class of investments are alternatives. These include everything else, from investing in land to investing in renewables. While it ranges, alternatives often incur the largest amount of risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While over recent years many investment companies have offered 0% commissions, allowing an individual to trade stocks or bonds ultimately for free, in other cases you may find yourself needing a financial advisor to help you navigate. You want to assure they are a fiduciary, a recent legal requirement, and that they have no conflicts of interest. You also want to assure that they are &lt;a href=&quot;https://money.usnews.com/investing/articles/2017-05-17/what-is-a-registered-investment-advisor&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;registered&lt;/a&gt; with the SEC. If you are paying commissions, this is generally fine, as long as you keep your commissions under 1%. Be on the lookout for hidden fees, and if you’re really worried, you can ask for a copy of their Form ADV, required by the SEC. You can look them up on &lt;a href=&quot;Brokercheck.finra.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;databases&lt;/a&gt; for “background checking”. You can also ask to see a sample portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;retirement-accounts&quot;&gt;Retirement accounts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many workplaces offer retirement plans, managed accounts where a percentage of your paycheck is paid into an account designed to save money for retirement. The most common of which is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/1/401kplan.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;401(k)&lt;/a&gt;. In some cases, each contribution to this account may be matched by your employer. Traditional 401(k) contributions are pre-tax, which means that while contributions are not taxed, withdrawals are. However, this also reduces your total taxable income for that year, with contributions deducted. Given that these accounts are designed as retirement savings, you must meet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/retirement-plans/retirement-plans-faqs-regarding-iras-distributions-withdrawals&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;age or other requirements&lt;/a&gt; to avoid penetalies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another popular retirement account is a  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/r/rothira.asp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Roth IRA&lt;/a&gt;, which is funded by post-tax income. This means you pay taxes on your contributions, but not when you withdraw the funds during retirement. For example, say you, as a 20-year-old, put $5,000 a year into a Roth IRA for 10 years, and then stop contributing. The 10 years of Roth contributions and growth—let’s assume at 8% interest a year to age 65—could total upwards of $1,070,944 of tax-free dollars. Given how advantageous these accounts can be to building wealth, there are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.irs.gov/retirement-plans/roth-iras&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;rules&lt;/a&gt; about how much and when you can contribute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lastly-some-ad-hoc-advice&quot;&gt;Lastly, some &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; advice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disassociate your self-worth from your net-worth. You’re doing amazing things, pushing humanity forward. &lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt; are more valuable than any number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend setting up alerts on your most often used bank accounts, whether text, email, or both. Not only will it help you keep a running sense for how much you’re spending, it can also help with detecting fraud in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself having a difficult time saving each month, many accounts can be set up to make automatic contributions to cash and retirement accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.profellow.com/tips/how-to-negotiate-your-funding-offer-for-graduate-school-an-email-template/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;negotiate&lt;/a&gt; your stipend?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of my favorite advice was to think of a research lab as a start-up company. There really are a lot of parallels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are now great tools to see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ogrants.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;open grants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or tools to &lt;a href=&quot;https://experiment.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;crowdsource science funding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little saved is better than nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like looking at national averages to put things into perspective. Average salary or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketwatch.com/picks/heres-exactly-how-much-americans-have-in-savings-at-every-age-and-yikes-heres-what-they-should-have-01659384531#&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;average savings&lt;/a&gt; (The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.federalreserve.gov/econres/scfindex.htm&quot;&gt;average savings&lt;/a&gt; of Americans under 35 in 2019 was $3,240)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stuff is complex, almost by design. Don’t ever be afraid to ask for help. Oh boy did I have to!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh by the way, Keiland is not a financial advisor (even though, technically, &lt;a href=&quot;https://money.usnews.com/money/personal-finance/family-finance/articles/2018-08-16/who-can-be-a-financial-advisor#:~:text=%22Anyone%20can%20pretty%20much%20call,of%20the%20Financial%20Planning%20Association.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;anyone can legally say that they are&lt;/a&gt;). This content is for educational purposes only, so please don’t construe any such information or material as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice. There are risks associated with investing in securities, and people can lose a lot of their hard earned money. Nothing contained on this site constitutes a solicitation, recommendation, endorsement, or offer by Keiland. Instead, he simply found navigating all of this to be a big pain in the butt, and had to learn most of this himself over time. So he thinks that helping folks navigate it might make scientists life a bit better, so they can make the world a bit better too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comming soon!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a question? Think I got an important topic wrong? Please let me know &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwcooper.xyz/contact&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Keiland Cooper</name></author><summary type="html">In an ideal world, scientists wouldn’t have to worry about finances and could focus on their research. In reality, like every other sector, macro- and micro-economic trends guide the shape of science. This pinch of reality reveals the complex systems that pervade all levels of academia: funding agencies, state legislation, donors, graduate stipends, or undergraduate tuition. Similar to other academic topics, I found this complex area difficult to navigate as an early scientist. Particularly as a first generation student, who once didn’t know the difference between bursar and provost, despite its importance, it’s rarely explicitly taught. Since then, I’ve spent years in academia, learning about through osmosis, and even did an MBA to help wrap my head around it all. What follows is a collection of some of my notes on the topic.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/blog/blog-post-05.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/blog/blog-post-05.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Some advice about grants like the NSF GRFP</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/GRFP-advice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some advice about grants like the NSF GRFP" /><published>2022-01-03T13:11:27-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-03T13:11:27-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/GRFP-advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/GRFP-advice/">&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to win the NSF GRFP award. I found online resources to be tremendously helpful. One day I’ll write a more thorough document about the GRFP. But honestly, many have already done a such a wonderful job that mine would only be mediocre in comparison. So I’ll point to some of the best resources and tips I know of, and then offer just a few bullets of my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m guessing you already know what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsfgrfp.org/&quot;&gt;the GRFP&lt;/a&gt; is, but if not, here is what the NSF says about it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The NSF GRFP recognizes and supports outstanding graduate students in NSF-supported STEM disciplines who are pursuing research-based master’s and doctoral degrees at accredited US institutions. The five-year fellowship includes three years of financial support including an annual stipend of $34,000 and a cost of education allowance of $12,000 to the institution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about applying, it’s definitely worth it, if for nothing else the experience of this type of writing and crystalizing your research. That said, it is a lot of work, so hopefully this can help serve as a jumping off point for resources, ideas, and tips I found to be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-resources&quot;&gt;Some resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsfgrfp.org/&quot;&gt;THE SOLICITATION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the next few months, this will be your life. Read. Every. Word. Seriously. I’ve heard too many stories of rejected grants because of a new formatting change, or a missed deadline (5pm, what an odd one to pick.) Every year is slightly different, so you can’t always trust outdated advice. So read this. Take notes. You will have worked too hard to miss a minor detail. NSF also puts on workshops overviewing that year’s grant, which can be pretty helpful. &lt;a href=&quot;https://nsfgrfp.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/GRFP2021_Application_Overview_Presentation.pdf&quot;&gt;Here are some older slides&lt;/a&gt; from them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.malloryladd.com/nsf-grfp-advice.html&quot;&gt;Mallory Ladd’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mallory has put together a really comprehensive website overviewing the GRFP. A great way to distill all of the dense writing of the solicitation (but again, not a substitution!). She even has a recommended schedule to keep you on track (though I, uhm, didn’t quite adhere to it as much as I would have liked…)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alexhunterlang.com/nsf-fellowship&quot;&gt;Alex Lang’s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of my favorites and among the most helpful. He has curated &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1xoezGhbtcpg3BvNdag2F5dTQM-Xl2EELUgAfG1eUg0s/edit#gid=0&quot;&gt;a spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; of over 100 successful GRFPs, many which have reviewer comments. Read as many as you can to get a feel for the overall organization and writing styles involved in the grant process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://natureinparadise.github.io/blog/grfp-advice/&quot;&gt;Dave’s site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Short but sweet, Dave offers some really good tips that can help focus your writing and set your application apart.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=20kRV8_mfHU&quot;&gt;Advice from an NSF reviewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;By now you should have an idea about what the GRFP is, how it works, and some examples. But what should still be less clear is the most important part: the reviewers. Darren Lipomi was nice enough to pull back the curtain a bit. I recomend watching his video, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ALcI6Ulrv4U&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; from UNM. More content like this comes out each year, so running a quick Google search can offer some useful information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.research.gov/grfp/AwardeeList.do?method=loadAwardeeList&quot;&gt;Award Offers and Honorable Mentions List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This site offers a comprehensive list of all winners and honorable mentions for the GRFP. At some point you’re going to have written an application, one of the best things you can do is to get as many eyes on it as possible. Look up some folks you may know and reach out to see if they wouldn’t mind having a quick go at yours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/higgs_boson.png&quot; alt=&quot;XKCD-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;some-brief-advice&quot;&gt;Some brief advice&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your goal is to put an image in the reviewers mind that you have the potential to contribute to the scientific workforce of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Before you write:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read every word of the solicitation. Yes. Every word. Outline it even&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know the deadline. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read as many grants as you can get your hands on. Start pretending you are a reviewer when you read them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put yourself in the reviewer’s shoes. Every. Step. Of. The. Way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do a mini lit review around your topics of interest. Get a feel for the field you’re applying to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your personal statement should be a &lt;em&gt;story&lt;/em&gt; built on the puzzle pieces of your accomplishments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say where you’ve been, where you are, and where you are going&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to plan in powerpoint. Easy to move ideas around&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As you write:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the reference writers to your advantage, as a component of your story. They are a part of your application. Use them as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be organized. Iterate everything. Back up everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be careful with your first and last sentence of each paragraph, they’re most memorable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give your reviewers bullet points to write about&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Submitting and happily ever after:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between 2010 and 2020, about ~2,000 Fellowships &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nsf.gov/ehr/Pubs/grfpoutreach2021.pdf&quot;&gt;are awarded yearly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2017: ~13,200 Applications - ~15% success rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2018: ~12,400 Applications - ~16% success rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2019: ~12,200 Applications - ~16% success rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2020: ~12,900 Applications - ~16% success rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that no matter how hard you work, you can only alter the probability you’ll get the grant. But at the end of the day, it is mostly a stochastic process. Grab 100 pennies, toss them on the ground, and then grab three of the most shiny and then 13 others. This is probably as good of a process for picking winners as any. I read applications I thought were better than mine that didn’t win. Doesn’t mean that that are any less of a scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reviewer woes - remember the set you get is mostly stochastic and who knows what crazy things they may say. Don’t fret if you get a bad review. I had some really helpful, thoughtful comments, and I’ve had the inverse. So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you submit, forget about the grant. You did some good work out there. Treat yourself and then get back to work on your next project. It’s up to the Science Gods now :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Things to keep in mind:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications by applicant stage are considered separately: UG -&amp;gt; then 1st year -&amp;gt; then 2nd year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GRFP is probably contributing to scientific inequity. For more on these arguments, I recommend reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://smallpondscience.com/2015/04/01/nsf-graduate-fellowships-are-a-part-of-the-problem/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://mbarkdull.github.io/NSF-GRFP-Inequities/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.science.org/content/article/nsf-graduate-fellowships-disproportionately-go-students-few-top-schools&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Afterwords:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pay it forward. Science is collaborative. You had help to get where you are and the next generation that will solve the problems we face will need it to. Read their essays. Write a blog. Help out at disadvantaged schools. Anything you can do, you should try to. If you didn’t win, apply again, either to the GRFP or some other grant. Plenty of the brightest scientists didn’t have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/further_research_is_needed.png&quot; alt=&quot;another-XKCD-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have a quick question that wasn’t discussed here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can try my best to answer it if you head &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwcooper.xyz/contact&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Will you read my application?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably! Remember my background is in neuroscience, cognitive science, and AI, but I’m excited to see the breath of science that’s going on. Head &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwcooper.xyz/contact&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can I see a copy of your application?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes! I’ll upload it here soon, but for now, head &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kwcooper.xyz/contact&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Keiland Cooper</name></author><summary type="html">I was lucky enough to win the NSF GRFP award. I found online resources to be tremendously helpful. One day I’ll write a more thorough document about the GRFP. But honestly, many have already done a such a wonderful job that mine would only be mediocre in comparison. So I’ll point to some of the best resources and tips I know of, and then offer just a few bullets of my own.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/blog/blog-post-02.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/blog/blog-post-02.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">USE-LESS BRAND</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ui%20ux/2020/03/10/use-less-brand.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="USE-LESS BRAND" /><published>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ui%20ux/2020/03/10/use-less-brand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ui%20ux/2020/03/10/use-less-brand.html">&lt;p&gt;The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The watch has the following features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time and date displayed on the screen. Current time is in large numbers, date is in small numbers above it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light: Pressing the light button on the side of the watch activates a light while the button is pressed. Pressing and holding that button for 3 seconds turns on the light and keeps it on, until the button is held again for 3 seconds or up to 2 hours. After 2 hours, it will automatically turn off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alarm. A daily alarm may be set for a given time. The alarm may be enabled or disabled. When the alarm is enabled and the alarm time is reached, the watch will beep fast for 5 seconds, then slowly for 30 seconds, then fast for another 5 seconds. Pressing any button stops the alarm sound (in addition to performing its normal function).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timer. Timer mode shows a count-up timer that starts at 00:00. When the timer is started, it counts up. Pressing the start/stop button will pause the timer, pressing it again continues counting up. Pressing and holding the button for 3 seconds resets the timer to 00:00 and stops counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mystery answer. After entering this mode, the screen initially displays “ask now”. The user may ask a yes-or-no question aloud and press the start/stop button, this will display a randomly selected answer that is one of the following: “yeah”, “yeah right”, “no”, “no doubt”, “keep trying”, “keep dreaming”. Whenever the display has more than one word, only one word is displayed for 2 seconds, then the other word is displayed for 2 seconds, alternately. The answer is displayed until the user leaves this mode, or he/she presses start/stop again for a new answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: these strings are for the English version of the watch, we will need to use completely different strings in other countries without reprogramming the logic of the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user may cycle among all modes (date/time, timer, mystery answer) by pressing the mode button.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="[&quot;UI UX&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-one.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-one.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KIO TAPE</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/product%20label/2020/03/10/kio-tape.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KIO TAPE" /><published>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/product%20label/2020/03/10/kio-tape</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/product%20label/2020/03/10/kio-tape.html">&lt;p&gt;The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The watch has the following features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time and date displayed on the screen. Current time is in large numbers, date is in small numbers above it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light: Pressing the light button on the side of the watch activates a light while the button is pressed. Pressing and holding that button for 3 seconds turns on the light and keeps it on, until the button is held again for 3 seconds or up to 2 hours. After 2 hours, it will automatically turn off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alarm. A daily alarm may be set for a given time. The alarm may be enabled or disabled. When the alarm is enabled and the alarm time is reached, the watch will beep fast for 5 seconds, then slowly for 30 seconds, then fast for another 5 seconds. Pressing any button stops the alarm sound (in addition to performing its normal function).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timer. Timer mode shows a count-up timer that starts at 00:00. When the timer is started, it counts up. Pressing the start/stop button will pause the timer, pressing it again continues counting up. Pressing and holding the button for 3 seconds resets the timer to 00:00 and stops counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mystery answer. After entering this mode, the screen initially displays “ask now”. The user may ask a yes-or-no question aloud and press the start/stop button, this will display a randomly selected answer that is one of the following: “yeah”, “yeah right”, “no”, “no doubt”, “keep trying”, “keep dreaming”. Whenever the display has more than one word, only one word is displayed for 2 seconds, then the other word is displayed for 2 seconds, alternately. The answer is displayed until the user leaves this mode, or he/she presses start/stop again for a new answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: these strings are for the English version of the watch, we will need to use completely different strings in other countries without reprogramming the logic of the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user may cycle among all modes (date/time, timer, mystery answer) by pressing the mode button.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="[&quot;PRODUCT LABEL&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-four.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-four.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">OSEN CLOCK</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/product%20design/2020/03/10/osen-clock.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OSEN CLOCK" /><published>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/product%20design/2020/03/10/osen-clock</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/product%20design/2020/03/10/osen-clock.html">&lt;p&gt;The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The watch has the following features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time and date displayed on the screen. Current time is in large numbers, date is in small numbers above it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light: Pressing the light button on the side of the watch activates a light while the button is pressed. Pressing and holding that button for 3 seconds turns on the light and keeps it on, until the button is held again for 3 seconds or up to 2 hours. After 2 hours, it will automatically turn off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alarm. A daily alarm may be set for a given time. The alarm may be enabled or disabled. When the alarm is enabled and the alarm time is reached, the watch will beep fast for 5 seconds, then slowly for 30 seconds, then fast for another 5 seconds. Pressing any button stops the alarm sound (in addition to performing its normal function).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timer. Timer mode shows a count-up timer that starts at 00:00. When the timer is started, it counts up. Pressing the start/stop button will pause the timer, pressing it again continues counting up. Pressing and holding the button for 3 seconds resets the timer to 00:00 and stops counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mystery answer. After entering this mode, the screen initially displays “ask now”. The user may ask a yes-or-no question aloud and press the start/stop button, this will display a randomly selected answer that is one of the following: “yeah”, “yeah right”, “no”, “no doubt”, “keep trying”, “keep dreaming”. Whenever the display has more than one word, only one word is displayed for 2 seconds, then the other word is displayed for 2 seconds, alternately. The answer is displayed until the user leaves this mode, or he/she presses start/stop again for a new answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: these strings are for the English version of the watch, we will need to use completely different strings in other countries without reprogramming the logic of the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user may cycle among all modes (date/time, timer, mystery answer) by pressing the mode button.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="[&quot;PRODUCT DESIGN&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-two.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-two.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SEAMLESS WATCH</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rebrand/2020/03/10/seamless-watch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SEAMLESS WATCH" /><published>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rebrand/2020/03/10/seamless-watch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rebrand/2020/03/10/seamless-watch.html">&lt;p&gt;The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The watch has the following features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time and date displayed on the screen. Current time is in large numbers, date is in small numbers above it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light: Pressing the light button on the side of the watch activates a light while the button is pressed. Pressing and holding that button for 3 seconds turns on the light and keeps it on, until the button is held again for 3 seconds or up to 2 hours. After 2 hours, it will automatically turn off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alarm. A daily alarm may be set for a given time. The alarm may be enabled or disabled. When the alarm is enabled and the alarm time is reached, the watch will beep fast for 5 seconds, then slowly for 30 seconds, then fast for another 5 seconds. Pressing any button stops the alarm sound (in addition to performing its normal function).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timer. Timer mode shows a count-up timer that starts at 00:00. When the timer is started, it counts up. Pressing the start/stop button will pause the timer, pressing it again continues counting up. Pressing and holding the button for 3 seconds resets the timer to 00:00 and stops counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mystery answer. After entering this mode, the screen initially displays “ask now”. The user may ask a yes-or-no question aloud and press the start/stop button, this will display a randomly selected answer that is one of the following: “yeah”, “yeah right”, “no”, “no doubt”, “keep trying”, “keep dreaming”. Whenever the display has more than one word, only one word is displayed for 2 seconds, then the other word is displayed for 2 seconds, alternately. The answer is displayed until the user leaves this mode, or he/she presses start/stop again for a new answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: these strings are for the English version of the watch, we will need to use completely different strings in other countries without reprogramming the logic of the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user may cycle among all modes (date/time, timer, mystery answer) by pressing the mode button.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="[&quot;REBRAND&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-three.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-three.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KIO-TAPE BRAND</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/product%20label/2020/03/10/kio-tape-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KIO-TAPE BRAND" /><published>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-10T14:11:27-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/product%20label/2020/03/10/kio-tape-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/product%20label/2020/03/10/kio-tape-2.html">&lt;p&gt;The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The watch has the following features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time and date displayed on the screen. Current time is in large numbers, date is in small numbers above it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light: Pressing the light button on the side of the watch activates a light while the button is pressed. Pressing and holding that button for 3 seconds turns on the light and keeps it on, until the button is held again for 3 seconds or up to 2 hours. After 2 hours, it will automatically turn off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alarm. A daily alarm may be set for a given time. The alarm may be enabled or disabled. When the alarm is enabled and the alarm time is reached, the watch will beep fast for 5 seconds, then slowly for 30 seconds, then fast for another 5 seconds. Pressing any button stops the alarm sound (in addition to performing its normal function).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timer. Timer mode shows a count-up timer that starts at 00:00. When the timer is started, it counts up. Pressing the start/stop button will pause the timer, pressing it again continues counting up. Pressing and holding the button for 3 seconds resets the timer to 00:00 and stops counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mystery answer. After entering this mode, the screen initially displays “ask now”. The user may ask a yes-or-no question aloud and press the start/stop button, this will display a randomly selected answer that is one of the following: “yeah”, “yeah right”, “no”, “no doubt”, “keep trying”, “keep dreaming”. Whenever the display has more than one word, only one word is displayed for 2 seconds, then the other word is displayed for 2 seconds, alternately. The answer is displayed until the user leaves this mode, or he/she presses start/stop again for a new answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: these strings are for the English version of the watch, we will need to use completely different strings in other countries without reprogramming the logic of the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user may cycle among all modes (date/time, timer, mystery answer) by pressing the mode button.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="[&quot;PRODUCT LABEL&quot;]" /><summary type="html">The “Seamless Watch” watch has all the features that users expect in a digital watch, and some unusual features.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-four.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/projects/project-thumb-four.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>